<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hi! Welcome to my website on Siddharth</title>
    <link>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hi! Welcome to my website on Siddharth</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project 6 - Covid-19 Analysis and Prediction</title>
      <link>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/post/project-6/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/post/project-6/</guid>
      <description>Goal: Analyze the covid-19 trends along and compare countries on their covid response. Create a model that helps forecast the number of cases per day, week and month.
  SARS-COV_2 is spreading like wildfire which has upenended our lives and made the economy go in tatters. The goal of this project is to compare responses of different countries to this pandemic, which can enable countries to model their response in a similar way to succesful countries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 2 - Clustering Stocks with K-Means Algorithm</title>
      <link>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/post/project-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/post/project-2/</guid>
      <description>Basic Overview:   Goal: Create an algorithm that helps financial experts to categorize stocks with particular attributes in a specific cluster.
  Stock selection, outlier detection, portfolio creation are important mechanisms for the financial industry to maximize and strategize the right investments in the stock market. Therefore, using certain indicators (often latent factors) we would attempt to cluster the given stocks to enable data driven decision making.
  Clustering will help in pointing common attributes/characteristics the clustered stocks share.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 3 - House Price prediction</title>
      <link>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/post/project-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/post/project-3/</guid>
      <description>Goal: Create a model that helps potential home buyers to estimate the price of homes in a particular city.
  The prices of homes can fluctuate depending on the number of bedrooms and bathrooms, the location and the histroic growth of the housing market. This project tries to take into account all the attributes that influences the home pricing and give these attributes the fair weight that they use to influence the pricing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4 - Uber ride prediction</title>
      <link>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/post/project-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/post/project-4/</guid>
      <description>Goal: Create a model to predict the number of weekly riders a rideshare company like Uber should expect.
  Uber is a company that needs to be on top of their game to meet rideshare demands, if they underprepare to serve the number of potential riders they will lose big money. More importantly it will give more room for their competition to grow.
  Therefore, this model will help Uber to predict number of riders based on attributes such as population of a city, average income of residents of that city, and the average amount a rider spends on ride-share per week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 5 - Fraud Prevention</title>
      <link>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/post/project-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/post/project-5/</guid>
      <description>Goal: Create a model that helps banks in preventing fraud to spot fake currency.
  The cost of counterfit currency circulating in our economy has devastating affects that cab disfigure the economic aparatus. Banks are on the frontlines to help the governemnt in making sure the economy is operating flawlessly. This effort by humans alone is not possible.
  Therefore, this project uses data acquisition, cleaning, and algorithm testing to construct a model that helps banks detect fake currency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project 4: Descriptive analysis of Business using Power-BI</title>
      <link>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/post/project-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Apr 2020 10:58:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/post/project-1/</guid>
      <description>Goal: Identify business journey of an enterprise with offices all over the country
Tools used: Power BI, Excel, MySQL
  Link to Google</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>  You can write to me at: siddharth-sinha@outlook.com
  You can connect with me on LinkedIn at: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sidisready/
  You can visit my GitHub page at: https://github.com/Version-Max
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is 5G dangerous?</title>
      <link>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/my-op-ed/op_ed-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/my-op-ed/op_ed-1/</guid>
      <description>Let me analyze this for you</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is 5G dangerous?</title>
      <link>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/what-am-i-reading/books-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/what-am-i-reading/books-1/</guid>
      <description>Let me analyze this for you</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is P-value in simple english</title>
      <link>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/data-analytics-blogs/blog-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://version-max.github.io/siddharth_portfolio/data-analytics-blogs/blog-1/</guid>
      <description>Goal: Identify business journey of an enterprise with offices all over the country
Tools used: Power BI, Excel, MySQL
  Link to Google</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
